

## **Nathan Birrell**

January 2024 | github.com/nathanbirrell | linkedin.com/in/nathanbirrell | nathanbirrell@gmail.com

### **ABOUT ME:**

Software Engineer with 10+ years of technical experience, scaling-up software products and building great teams. Interested in senior front-end roles, full-stack and open to lead roles (remote preferred).

Australian Citizen with working rights in the EU. Located in Bologna, Italy from March 17.

### **KEY SKILLS:**

- Specialised frontend experience across React,
  Typescript, NextJS & CSS
- 2. Strong backend commercial experience with Node, GraphQL, Express, REST, both RDBMS & NoSQL
- 3. Solution architecture on AWS: Lambda, ECS, AppSync, DynamoDB, CDK

# **Experience**

### **MYOB**

### SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER (CONTRACT) • OCT 2023 - PRESENT

MYOB is an accounting SaaS business. I was brought onto the Web & Content team.

- Reduced inbound calls to support phone lines with the introduction of Support Article Search with Algolia. Built with reuse in mind, we used the same component on other areas of the website.
- Strategic guidance on architecture decisions around NextJS, localisation and partial prerendering.
- Other deliverables: core web vitals improvements; integration with headless CMS Contentful; middleware performance improvements; and a website rebrand.

# Stax (by Versent)

#### SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER • OCT 2018 - OCT 2023

Stax is a B2B SaaS AWS cloud management platform, which empowers teams to deliver on AWS with consistency, confidence and velocity. In October 2023, Stax & Versent sold to Telstra for \$267.5m.

- Ownership of long-term strategy for a production frontend application (20k+ LOC), a component library, style system and a backend API service (60k LOC).
- Led architecture/build for a backend-for-frontend project, to simplify interfacing with microservices
- Scaled-up engineering capabilities from 5 engineers to 30+, establishing best practices and processes for our growing organisation.
- Mentored and supported junior engineers, helping them grow their skills and confidence through pair programming, code reviews and leading workshops.
- Set-up best-practice foundations for our React app with unit testing, end-to-end tests, linting, CI processes and docs. Tooling snapshot: NextJS, React, Typescript, GraphQL, Lambda, DynamoDB.
- Increased consistency across multiple frontend projects and across Engineering and Design teams, with a style system and component library.
- Tech: Typescript, GraphQL, Apollo, React, Jest, Playwright, NodeJS, AWS Lambda, AppSync, DynamoDB Serverless, SQS, SAM, CDK and more.

### **Bureau of Meteorology**

SOFTWARE ENGINEER (CONTRACT) • MAR 2018 - OCT 2018

- A new weather experience for the general public in Australia's top 30 most visited websites
- Improved reliability and protyping speed with static typing & tree-structured state management lib

Belong (by Telstra)

FRONT-END DEVELOPER • NOV 2016 - MAR 2018

**Deloitte Digital** 

UI DEVELOPER (CONSULTANT) • JAN 2014 - NOV 2016

## Education

### **Bachelor of Business (Information Systems)**

2012-2015

Royal Melbourne Institute of Technology (RMIT University)

Applied course (industry placement), minor in Marketing, GPA 3.2